

#### SOFTWARE ARCHITECT | ENGINEERING MANAGER | PRINCIPAL CLOUD DEVELOPER

13 Norman Street , Lutwyche , Wooloowin , Brisbane , Queensland , Australia

□ (+61) 4880-31336 | we emailkushalmk@gmail.com | whttps://moghthalkushal.github.io/myloTProjects/ | woghthalkushal | we hall-m-k | we hall-m-k-068b4932

"Work is worship."

## **Summary**

Technology Agnostic Software Leader, Strategist, Architect, Tech Evangelist, Agile Practitioner, with hands on experience in software development (both front end and back end technologies). 10+ years experience specializing in the backend development, front end development, infrastructure automation, and IoT. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

#### **Emerson | Paradigm Solution**

Brisbane, Australia

PRINCIPAL CLOUD DEVELOPER

Nov. 2019 - Till Date

- Cloud first approach, laid out other cloud strategies for the organization, next gen tracing, logging and monitoring tools and other added analytics capabilities
- Built fully automated CI/CD pipelines using the existing systems in place
- Designed an overall architecture and pipelines for the next gen app capabilities
- · Legacy to cloud
- Started automated testing practices
- Open Source contributions for OSDU (open subsurface data universe)
- Vendor Team Managements, Design, Architecture and Code Reviews
- · Quick preview of the app geolog-osdu-integration

PCCW Global Brisbane , Australia

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - MANAGERIAL LEVEL

Aug. 2019 - Oct. 2019

- Tech and People Management leading a team 10
- User Experience Management
- Building internal and client facing web applications for port management, focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.
- Started TDD approach
- Developed an easy-to-use Payment for payments , a self service module , with all integrated test , to enable easy service activation , a sort of robotic process automation

Walmart Labs Bangalore , India

SENIOR ENGINEER | ARCHITECT | ASSOCIATE MANAGER

Jan. 2015 - Jun. 2019

- Code, Design and Architectural reviews
- Build scalable applications (internal application for retail link using Microsoft Technologies and other necessary tech)
- Build and Manage Data Pipelines (Azure data factory, SQL, Kafka, Azure Bus, Oozie, SSIS)
- Automated Tests, Support and documentation
- Tech Modernization re usable components and libraries , server less apps , dockerize apps , Legacy to Next Gen cloud , traditional web apps to spas using react or angular
- Participate in Agile Ceremonies
- Manage a team of 20 and collaborate with various other stakeholders
- Help cross functional teams, technically and in hiring operations
- · Organize team outings

G.E Bangalore , India

JUNIOR .NET DEVELOPER

• Developed internal Tools for GE Capital

Sep. 2014 - Jan. 2015

• Feature Enhancements - Continuous Delivery, ALM Fixes - Developing POC to prove the capabilities of latest technologies Technology Used: Microsoft Technologie

September 29, 2020 Kushal MK · Résumé 1

Siemens. Bangalore, India

Senior Systems Engineer Apr. 2012 - Sep. 2014

- Develop applications for Siemens healthcare, industry and Infrastructure business
- Intervene on the entire project lifecycle: review and understanding of business requirements, technical design, development, testing, implementation and maintenance
- Develop server-side components and web services, client-side user interfaces (ASP.Net /Node JS/ HTML 5 -CSS3, JS, Angular JS etc), as well
  as SQL databases, Store procedures, functions, triggers according to specifications
- Document, support end users by providing manuals and assistance tools
- · Stay up-to-date with technology and seek to be a well-certified professional according to Microsoft official certification tracks
- · Apply various design patterns while creating standard reusable templates across various software applications

NIC - Govt of India Bangalore , India

PROGRAMMER

Jul. 2011 - Apr. 2012

- Saved thousands of rupees by researching and implementing paperless office, cost-saving initiatives and creating fresh new approaches to long-standing problems
- · Introduced bio-metrics and saved a lot of money for the govt, technological approach to remove fraudulent monetary grants

### Awards & Patents\_

#### AWARDS

Finalist and Winners, also in (2016), Hackathons at Walmart

Exceeded Expectation, till 2018, Walmart Internal Employee Review - Got promoted twice in 4 years and

Bangalore

Bangalore

#### **PATENTS**

2019 Targeted advertisement system,
2017 Automated Resume Screening,
US

## **Presentation**

#### Shaping careers in IT hosted by ATME College of Engineering

multiple hikes and salary revisions

Brisbane, Australia and India

Presenter for < Career Opportunities for a Computer Science Graduate>

Aug. 2020

- Explained various career options for young engineers , in the field of computer science

Emerson Internal Event Brisbane, Australia

PRESENTER FOR < MICRO FRONT ENDS AND PRIVATE NPM>

Nov. 2019

 $\bullet \ \ \text{Introduced the history of web technology , micro services and explained the benefits and overheads of Micro front ends}$ 

Walmart Internal Event Bangalore, India

PRESENTER FOR < IOT IN RETAILS>

Jul. 2017

• Explained possible use cases of IoT in retail using arudino and raspberry-pi

## Other Achievements and Activities

Jan. 2011 - PRESENT

- Minimized corruption, paperless office when deployed as a programmer at fedral govt departments
- · Process work flow automation, reducing a lot of effort/ Manpowerat Siemens and received a lot of appreciation from the management.
- Centre of excellence within 6 months of Joining at Walmart
- Key member for hiring, helped many teams scale, we scaled our team from 10 to 106
- Mentor and Innovator , helped many cross functional teams across organizations
- Key member in exploring new tech and learning strategy, was in charge of exploring and recommending udemy, plural sight and other learning development platforms for organizations

### **Education**

#### Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani

India

MASTER OF TECHNOLOGY IN SOFTWARE SYSTEMS

Jun. 2013 - Jun. 2015

• Final year project - e-PHR for Walmart

#### BTLIT - vishweshwaraiah technological university

Bangalore, India Jun. 2007 - Jun. 2011

BACHELORS OF ENGINEERING IN INFORMATION SCIENCE

• Final year project - mobile cloud computing

SEPTEMBER 29, 2020 KUSHAL MK · RÉSUMÉ

# **Hands on experience**

#### FRONT END

- HTML5, Javascript, react, react native, angular, jquery
- gulp , bower , npmbootstrap , material-ui
- D3 , plotly , leaflet , cypress

#### BACK END

- Dockers and K8s
- C#,.NET, and .NET Core , ASP.NET MVC, WEB API , SSRS/SSIS/SSDT , EF and N-Hibernates , Azure and Most of the Microsoft Tech Stack
- Node Js, express
- Python, Tornado
- Distributed Systems and Big Data Systems Kafka , Hive
- R-Pi, Arduino, IoT, MQTT